<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>technology on Terminal</title>
    <link>/categories/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in technology on Terminal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 11:20:54 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Cli Tool in Rust</title>
      <link>/post/building-a-cli-tool-in-rust/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 11:20:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/building-a-cli-tool-in-rust/</guid>
      <description>Like almost everyone I know, I’ve been sitting pacing inside for almost 8 weeks, waiting out the sars-cov-2 pandemic. I’ve been “zooming” with friends, phoning my family members, and catching up on reading. Gone are the days of concerts and movie theaters. Now is the time for reading, Animal Crossing, and updating one’s websites. So here it is, a new theme for a new year and a new post to help stave off boredom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional Programming in Racket</title>
      <link>/post/functional-programming-in-racket/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 11:14:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/functional-programming-in-racket/</guid>
      <description>A dive into functional programming in Racket.
Preface I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing around with functional languages for a few years now; I&amp;rsquo;d pick up an ebook on scala or Clojure some Saturday afternoon and try going through a tutorial or two. Maybe attend a workshop on it over a weekend with a friend who found the event on meetup.com and get a somewhat shallow overview of the language. The next weekend I&amp;rsquo;d look at it again and see if I could get a small webpage up and running or maybe a small command line tool but for the most part, it has always ended there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading Parquet Files With Java</title>
      <link>/post/reading-parquet-files-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 12:41:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/reading-parquet-files-java/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A simple way of reading Parquet files without the need to use Spark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently ran into an issue where I needed to read from &lt;a href=&#34;https://parquet.apache.org/&#34;&gt;Parquet&lt;/a&gt; files in a simple way without having to use the entire Spark framework. Though inspecting the contents of a Parquet file turns out to be pretty simple using the &lt;code&gt;spark-shell&lt;/code&gt;, doing so without the framework ended up being more difficult because of a lack of documentation about how to read the actual content of Parquet files, the columnar format used by Hadoop and Spark.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>