<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rust on Adam&#39;s Blag</title>
    <link>/tags/rust/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rust on Adam&#39;s Blag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Adam Melnyk 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 15:45:10 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/rust/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging CHIP8 code</title>
      <link>/post/debugging-chip8-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 15:45:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/debugging-chip8-code/</guid>
      <description>The first time I wrote a program in hexidecimal or assembly was using a made up, educational cpu called Pep8, this was before I had read anything about how to properly organize code, programming practices, and before I had read clean code. Over the last month and a half, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a CHIP8 emulator, so for the first time in a while, I&amp;rsquo;m revisiting old topics and old books on computer architecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scraping Wikipedia With Rust</title>
      <link>/post/scraping-wikipedia-with-rust/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 23:15:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/scraping-wikipedia-with-rust/</guid>
      <description>Writing a toy scraper As the quarantine continues and many things are still closed, I&amp;rsquo;m still spending a lot of time looking for fun side projects I can complete in a few days or less. As I drifted off to sleep one night wondering about some correlations between countries and various other data points. I realized that wikipedia probably had all the data I needed to find out. What if I could just scrape all the data off of wikipedia and throw it into sql tables so I could chart data that way?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Cli Tool in Rust</title>
      <link>/post/building-a-cli-tool-in-rust/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 11:20:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/building-a-cli-tool-in-rust/</guid>
      <description>Like almost everyone I know, I’ve been sitting pacing inside for almost 8 weeks, waiting out the sars-cov-2 pandemic. I’ve been “zooming” with friends, phoning my family members, and catching up on reading. Gone are the days of concerts and movie theaters. Now is the time for reading, Animal Crossing, and updating one’s websites. So here it is, a new theme for a new year and a new post to help stave off boredom.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>